

# SOHEL AHMED **ANSARI**

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

+971564710320 sohel.ahmed.ansari@gmail.com

## **SKILLS**

React

Stripe Payments API

JQuery

Javascript (ES6)

**HTML** 

CSS (Less)

Nodejs

Webpack

Git

TypeScript

Scrum

## **HOBBIES**

Video Games, Cooking, Travelling

## **EDUCATION**

**BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING** M.H. SABOO SIDDIK COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING | MUMBAI 2009

## LINKS

Website: https://sohelansari.com

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sohela

Stackoverflow:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/22 79116/shinobi

#### ABOUT ME

Experienced in everything from converting designs into functional pages to setting up complex applications in modern frameworks.

Specialized in handling front-end development and dealing with UI and UX of anything that I work on. I am always interested to put my views on the look and feel of the product.

History of working effectively in agile environments. Disciplined and hardworking team player.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (UI PLATFORM)

Working as Senior front-end engineer in the UI Platform team.

FORTO LOGISTICS SE & CO. KG. | BERLIN MAY 2022 - PRESENT

Tools and technologies include: React, Material UI, Nodejs, HTML, CSS, webpack, Storybook, Datadog, CircleCI, Jest, Cypress, Figma

My role includes:

- Collaborate closely with the design team to spearhead the development of an elegant design system, empowering front-end engineers to create visually stunning user interfaces.
- existing component library, resulting in a more efficient and consistent user experience. Drive a user-centric approach by identifying pain points and challenges in the

• Elevate the quality of our front-end ecosystem by enhancing and expanding the

- front-end development process, leading to substantial improvements in the developer experience. Foster a sense of community and knowledge sharing within the Forto front-end
- community, staying at the forefront of industry trends and best practices. • Improve pipelines to reduce development time and costs, ensuring efficient

project delivery and resource utilization.

- Maintain and validate our front-end stack, leveraging the latest technologies and frameworks to keep our applications at the cutting edge of innovation.
- Facilitate seamless cross-team collaboration by effectively communicating and coordinating efforts between various departments, ensuring project success and alignment with organizational goals.
- Uphold the highest coding standards and best practices, guaranteeing that our front-end codebase remained clean, maintainable, and scalable.
- Empower cross-functional teams to proactively monitor and improve code quality by enabling the creation of operational metrics, including code coverage, identification of deviations in code, and tracking outdated library usage, thereby enhancing overall codebase health and reliability.

Notable achievements:

- Helped build a token based design system with seamless integrations between github and Figma where designers can push changes in color and typography from Figma directly into our components library in github without any manual coding needed from developers.
- Generated metrics for things like code coverage and deviations in design system which is automatically pushed to Datdadog as part of the deploy pipeline which will help teams to track the quality of code over time
- Enabled teams to be able to gradually migrate from Material UI v4 to v5 by setting up the front-end apps to run both version at the same time. This enabled teams to parallely migrate without having to stop feature development
- Significant contribution to our components library (React, MUI, Storybook)
- Made significant improvements to our build pipelines in CircleCI

#### SENIOR PROGRAMMER ONE.COM | DUBAI

MAY 2016 - APR 2022 Worked on front-end and backend development of Webshop

(https://www.one.com/en/webshop)

**PostgreSQL** 

Technologies included: React, Knockout.js, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, NodeJS,

My role included:

using Stripe

- Developing pixel perfect UI from given design and making it functional in React Converting existing Knockout.js code to React.
- Writing handlers in backend which is in Node.js and familiar with writing queries
- in PostgreSQL. Have worked on integrating payments through Credit card, iDEAL and Giropay
- Acting as the communicator between my team of 5 developers with me in Dubai and the Project Manager in Copenhagen.
- Responsible for keeping an eye on the progress of the Sprint and making sure that the product manager is informed about any changes in it.
- Follow scrum methodology and Agile Software Development strategy.

#### NEXSALES CORPORATION | MUMBAI NOV 2014 - APR 2016

SENIOR PROGRAMMER

Worked on front-end development of a web app VoiceReach used by BPO for

reaching out to prospects for marketing. It was a single page web application written in AngularJS 1.3

Technologies include: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, AngularJS 1.3, Bootstrap, NodeJS

My role included:

Getting involved in feature discussions and giving inputs on the UI/UX.

 Developing in AngularJS which includes creating HTML templates, styling CSS, writing code for angular controller, directive and services.

• Follow scrum methodology and Agile Software Development strategy.

- Integrating external angular directives and using it.
- SOFTWARE ENGINEERING SR. ANALYST

ACCENTURE | MUMBAI

FEB 2014 - NOV 2014

making templates for given psds and making it functional. Making sure the page is

Worked on front-end development of a retail company client. Work included

# responsive on all devices.

Technologies include: HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Sass, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Backbone.js

SENIOR PROGRAMMER

ZEUS SYSTEMS PVT. LTD. | MUMBAI JUL 2009 - JAN 2014

Worked on many e-learning products to help kids of different age groups learn Maths and Science.

Technologies include: HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Backbone.js, ActionScript 3,

Flash